### Resume

# Morteza Alipour - Frontend Developer

Tehran, Irar

(98) 991-0511-071 MORTEZAALIPOUR.IR LINKEDIN GITHUB TELEGRAM MORTEZAALIPOUR1777@GMAIL.COM

### **Skills**

Nearly 7 years of experience in **front-end** development with expertise in **React**, **JavaScript**, **Next JS**, **Tailwind**, **Redux**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **Typescript**, **Node JS**, **Express JS**, **MongoDB**, **Three JS**, **Git**, **Storybook**, **jQuery**, **Figma**, and other technologies. Strong interest in learning new technologies and driving projects from concept to launch. Excited about learning and development with a desire to apply skills on a larger team. Eager to tackle more complex problems and continue to find ways to maximize user efficiency.

React js	Next js	Javascript	HTML/CSS	Redux
React-Query	React-Testing-Library	Node js	Tailwind	Bootstrap
jQuery	Git	Typescript	MongoDB	Express js
Three js	Figma	Storybook	signal-R	WebSocket

## **Experience**

Jun 2021 - Present

## **QUBY, Tehran - Iran -** Frontend Developer

- Developed a web application that attracted more than 25,000 users.
- Mentored 1 intern, guiding him in developing and using new and high-end technologies.
- Managed about 3 projects related to the IoT, such as vending machines and remote elevator controls.
- Implemented responsive and user-friendly web interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for more than 10 projects, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement.
- Contributed closely with 3 designers and 2 back-end developers to successfully integrate and implement user interface designs.
- Conducted daily code reviews for an intern, providing timely feedback and teaching new methods and best practices.
- Proficient in functional programming concepts.
- Participated in producing maintainable code in large codebases in more than 4 projects.
- Utilized 2 different types of version control systems such as Git and Azure.

#### **DATIS, Tehran - Iran -** *Frontend Developer*

- Collaborated with 2 back-end developers to develop three Admin dashboard templates.
- Achieved a 40% improvement in website performance by strategically reducing page load times, resulting in enhanced overall site functionality.
- Optimized one website's quality by promptly addressing bugs through debugging and testing, ensuring robust and seamless user experiences.
- Utilized front-end automation tools and task runners.
- Designed 3 dashboard admin panels for warehouse and distribution functions.

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

#### Freelance, Lahijan - Iran - Frontend Developer

- Mentored 2 intern front-end developers in learning and developing projects.
- Conducted comprehensive compatibility testing for applications and websites across various devices and browsers.
- Created one financial application powered by two powerful technologies, Angular and Electron, for Windows and macOS.
- Developed more than 5 projects, including A-EYES (measuring eye dryness) and Bencherz (Football Fantasy), utilizing Angular and React.

Jan 2017- Apr 2019

#### NilaSoft, Rasht - Iran - Frontend Developer

- Collaborated with a UI/UX designer and 2 front-end developers to seamlessly integrate visually captivating and intuitive user interfaces.
- Coordinated with three backend developers to implement changes and conduct testing for more than 2 websites.
- Integrated third-party APIs and libraries, enhancing website functionality and optimizing user experience, resulting in a 25% increase in engagement of users.
- Implemented 2 responsive websites using the Angular framework.

## **Education**

Sep 2014 - Jun 2019

Guilan University, Rasht - Iran - Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

## Certificates

MERN stack | Udemy | React + Redux | SoloLearn | Javascript | SoloLearn | HTML | SoloLearn |

## Language

Persian (Native) English (C1)